Taylor McClerin

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER · LinkedIn · GitHub · Site

PROFILE: Public, private, and non-profit professional with software engineer aspirations. Recent graduate of App Academy with full stack capacity. Ten years of customer service experience, two years of managing in a for-profit environment, three years of international, non-profit experience managing direct services projects, and three years of public service experience. Strong leadership skills include training, task delegation, time management, and conflict resolution in volunteer and program coordination. Experienced in developing and executing M&E frameworks and applying results to program development.

LANGUAGES:

JavaScript(JS), Python, Structured Query Language (SQL), Hypertext Markup Language (HTML), Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), Git, R

FRAMEWORKS:

Sequelize, Express, SQLAlchemy, Flask, React, React-redux, Node.js

TOOLS:

Github, Amazon Web Services(AWS)

OTHER:

Statistical Product and Service Solutions (SPSS), Geographical Information Systems (GIS), Project coordination and management, Microsoft Office Software including Excel, French (advanced fluency) & Spanish (novice fluency)

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

SOIL MATES · Python · Flask · SQLAlchemy · React · Git · CSS · Mapbox

<u>GitHub Repo</u> · <u>Live Site</u>

- Employed Mapbox API with International Soil Research Information Center (ISRIC) API so users can click on a map to query soil data for that location, allowing for simple data retrieval without the need for knowing coordinates
- Implemented posting, commenting, and voting features which allow for users to share soil data and information similar to Stack Overflow
- Utilized React Redux to manage state and normalize data, providing for smooth scaling into larger traffic and data sets
- Implemented AWS functionality to provide user with optional profile picture and to allow them to customize their profile

 ${\sf EVERY\ NOTE \cdot Python \cdot Flask \cdot SQLAlchemy \cdot React \cdot Git \cdot CSS}$

GitHub Repo · Live Site

- Managed git pull requests and merge conflicts in amicable group setting to create a clone of Ever Note in under two weeks
- Implemented Flask database backend and React front end to provide users with a note-taking function organized by notebooks and tags as well as a tasks keeper to reinforce user organization
- In combination with React-Redux store, organized components in a way to provide snappy response time to users with full CRUD functionality.

FAIR BNB \cdot JS \cdot Express \cdot React \cdot Git \cdot CSS

GitHub Repo · Live Site

- Created clone of Airbnb with an emphasis on modal use as a means to expedite functionality
- Implemented Express backend with React-redux front end to provide quick response times for user
- Created rating system which dynamically responded to base calculations
- Employed AWS as a means for storing spot photos to provide longer-term data stability

EDUCATION

App Academy · Full Stack Web Development

Graduated July 2023

JS, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS, Git, SQLite3, Express, SQLAlchemy, Flask, React, Git, AWS, Node is

DePaul University · Chicago, IL

Graduated August 2022

Master of Science in Public Policy

University of North Carolina Asheville · Asheville, NC

Graduated May 2013

- Bachelor of Science in Biology
- Bachelor of Arts in French

RECENT EMPLOYMENT

VETERANS BENEFIT ADMINISTRATION (VBA) · Veterans Service Representative (VSR) · Chicago, IL

Sep 2019 - Aug 2022

- Served as the Homeless Veterans Claims Coordinator (HVCC), coordinating care and paperwork for homeless veterans to expedite benefit awards resulting in a 30-90% reduction in wait time
- Determined compensation eligibility by requesting, analyzing, and developing medical evidence
- Utilized various data processing systems to adjudicate, monitor, evaluate, and prepare correspondence
- Served as a primary contact for the veteran, advocating for disability benefits for them and their beneficiaries

- Directly and indirectly supported J-1 visa participants in navigating work, travel, and housing concerns by ensuring their health, welfare, and safety during their program
- · Reviewed applications and vetted participant employers according to Department of State regulations
- Generated daily and weekly reports via database systems to support program management

PEACE CORPS (PC) TOGO Reforestation Monitoring and Evaluation (M&E) Specialist · Togo, W. Africa

Jun 2015 - Sep 2018

- Managed cashew plantation projects by organizing community members, developing and constructing nurseries, collecting inputs (seed, manure, et cetera), maintaining and caring for seedlings, preparing sites, and organizing workdays. I organized community members to execute the planting of five (5) hectares of trees
- Trained and supervised a team of four Togolese and four PC Volunteers to conduct long term assessment of reforestation initiatives in rural Togo, conducted 41 site visits throughout the country, and generated a comprehensive outcomes report to redesign PC Togo's agroforestry program
- Wrote *Peace Corps Togo Reforestation Manual, 2018, pp 82*, with results-oriented reforestation techniques within a West African environmental and social context to improve reforestation, gender, and food security outcomes which has been distributed to each subsequent volunteer cohort since.
- Conducted comprehensive on-site needs assessment. In response trained, and coordinated a team of Togolese volunteers to cofacilitate 89 community trainings across five (5) villages for 663 adults and youth in reforestation, sustainable agriculture, nutrition, and environmental stewardship.
- · Ensured volunteer acknowledgement and appreciation resulting in repeat participation in different events

TOD'S CAFÉ Assistant Manager (2012-2015).

- Managed bakery within a café that served 350 clients daily, grossing over \$300,000 annually
- Efficiently directed daily product delivery between sister restaurants, processed customers' special requests, and fulfilled catering orders
- Onboarded, trained, supervised, and managed staff meetings for five personnel
- Managed inventory, ordering, scheduling, and pricing to support senior management